bumper plates are an awesome solution
for anybody who wants to work in some
power lifts and Olympic style lifts in
their home gym the rubber coating on the
style of weight plate makes them
extremely versatile since the barbell
can be dropped and you know not yet
completely ruined at the same time now
there's a ton of bumper plates for you
to choose from out there but I figured
I'd go and compare two awesome options
for you guys this pair from Rogue and
this pair from rep Fitness let's get to
it
[Music]
what's up my friends it's Jake back in
the barbing garage gym with another
comparison review ready to go for y'all
this time I'm going to be comparing
these Rogue bumper plates to these rep
Fitness bumper plates and I'm gonna help
you decide which ones need to be tossed
around your home gym but before I get
going with all that I got to let you
know we've reviewed a ton of bumper
plates on barbin.com and if you want to
look at our top picks just go and search
bar Bend best bumper plates and you can
find out for yourself which one takes
home that number one spot foreign
so let's talk about some similarities
and differences between these two bumper
plates but I gotta be honest other than
the fact that they kind of look alike
they both feature steel inserts and a
low bounce virgin rubber these are
essentially two completely different
products now let's talk about the actual
size of each bumper plate first and
foremost the thickness the diameters are
basically the exact same but the
thickness
the rep Fitness bumper plates are
significantly thicker than the Rogue one
so I'm going to be comparing the 45s for
you guys today so these 45 pound plates
are about 2.4 inches thick well these
45s from rep they're about 2.8 inches
thick both of these companies do offer
full sets when it comes to purchasing
these bumper plates the rep actually has
a heavier set they offer as well as more
sets overall and when you look at these
bumper plates priced individually
Rogue actually has theirs priced a
little bit cheaper but when it's all
said and done your Rogue plates are
gonna cost you more because of shipping
which is something you don't have to pay
for if you go with rep Fitness rep is
also going to toss in warranties with
their bumper plates while Rogue actually
does not do that Rogue also mentions the
durometer rating of their bumper plates
while with rep they actually don't do
that so if you don't know what a
durometer rating is it's essentially
going to tell you how hard an object is
and when it comes to Bumper plates how
much bounce you can expect to happen
when they're dropped so with bumper
plates this typically ranges anywhere
from 65 to 100 with 100 being the least
amount of balance that you're going to
find so these Rogue bumper plates
feature a rating right at 88 which is
really solid and well you know with
these rep plates there's definitely not
a whole lot of Bounce you just don't
know what that exact rating is
foreign
[Music]
okay so let's talk about some money now
when it comes to individual pairs these
bumper plates are available for right
around the same price but at the end of
the day you're going to be spending some
more money if you were to go with Rogue
so for example these 45 pound plates
from rep Fitness are Priced Right Around
200 bucks all these from Rogue are going
to run you around 190 but with Rogue you
do in fact have to pay 40 bucks or so
for shipping well with rep you actually
have free shipping and this is going to
be the case with every single weight
option offered by both of these
companies that original price tag with
rep is going to be more expensive than
Rogues but you know because you do have
free shipping with rep you're going to
be saving money than if you were to go
with the Rogue bumper plates now when it
comes to the full sets I already
mentioned that rep has more for you to
purchase but let's focus on the three
sets available with both of these
companies 160 pound set 230 pound and
260 pound set you're gonna be saving
about 50 bucks or so with every single
one of those if you were to go with rep
now it's worth mentioning that Rogue
actually does not charge you for
shipping when it comes to their full
sets but you're still going to be
spending a little bit more money so if
you do in fact want to save some of that
cash
I'd suggest you go in with rep
okay so let's talk about the build and
some of the features now with both of
these bumper plates but I want to
highlight Rogues first now once again
you do have steel inserts and they're
wrapped in a low bounce virgin rubber
coating these also have a durometer
rating of 88 so that way you know if
you're doing some power cleans throw
that barbell onto the ground they're not
going to bounce too much so that's
pretty nice now these do have a uniform
diameter it's an iwf standard of 17.7
inches but the thickness is definitely
you know going to change depending on
which weight you're going with and I got
to say before I give you all of this
these are some of the thinnest bumper
plates that I've ever used that could be
a cause of concern for some people but I
personally think it's just fine they
seem really durable and if you're
loading up a lot of weight you know
that shock absorption is going to be you
know spread out with the other plates on
there so I think you'll be just fine I
think that's more so gonna be something
to worry about for people who are you
know just throwing one plate on there
and because that case you do you know
run the risk of the plates bending a
little bit over time now the 10 pound
plates are right around eight tenths of
an inch thick the 15s are a little over
an inch thick the 25s are about 1.5
inches thick or so 35s are right at 1.9
and these 45s once again are right at
2.4 inches thick so you can really load
on a bunch of these plates on either end
of your barbell and really you know get
that super heavy lift that you're
looking for obviously they're black in
color and they do have white letterings
you know nice little contrast right
there makes it super easy to see you
know what exact weight you're working
out with if you aren't crazy about the
black coloring they do offer these Echo
bumper plates in a colored option but I
gotta say you know those are going to be
more expensive and it doesn't really
change your workout in any way possible
it just might make it a little bit
easier for you to you know pick which
weight you're using and you might just
like the aesthetic better
all right now if we transition to the
rep plates you know these also feature
steel inserts with a low balance virgin
rubber coating they also could last you
about 10 years or so as long as you take
the proper care of them these actually
have a diameter of 17.5 inches so it
does not meet the iwf standard and the
thickness is also going to you know vary
depending on which weight option that
you're using so I think it's pretty cool
how their 10-pound plates are actually
thicker than most 10-pound bumper plates
they're right at one inch thick so
that's gonna you know make them more
durable in the long run the 15s are
right around one and a quarter inch
thick 25s or one and three quarter
inches thick 35s are about 2.4 inches
thick and these 45s are right around 2.8
2.83 inches thick and I gotta say you
know right at first glance you can
definitely tell how much thicker these
are and you know it's designed to be
able to help you you know load on
heavier weight for your lifts but you
know they're definitely thicker than
these 40 35 some Rogues so you could
actually load on more weight with these
Rogue Echo bumper plates and similar to
the Rogue Echo plates you know these
from rep they're also black in color
with white lettering makes it super easy
to see which weight you're using but you
know if you have a soft spot and you
just really want some Olympic style
colored plates rep offers that but you
know similar to Rogue they're going to
be more expensive and I don't know if
that's worth spending that extra money
all right y'all let's go into a quick
walk around with both of these bumper
plates I'm going to kick this off with
the diameter of each you know once again
these Rogue plates do in fact feature
the iwf standard diameter of 17.7 inches
go and measure that out here and as you
can see it's right there on it now
rep 17.5 inches in diameter and I'm
going to measure that for you as well
and as you can see it's right there on
17.7 inches so that's something that you
you know have a really big emphasis on
you do want that iwf standard you're
going to want to go with Rogue now I'm
going to rotate both of these
off the bat it's not hard to tell that
these rep plates are significantly
thicker than these right here from Rogue
that could definitely impact some people
you know with their workouts especially
if you're wanting to do some super heavy
lifts you're going to have more space on
the barbell if you were to go with
Rogues plates so this 45 is 2.4 inches
thick now you know what I'm going to do
here I'm going to go ahead and measure
this out for you as you can see it's
right there on it
now if we go over to these rep plates
you know they're almost three inches
thick these are actually still thinner
than a lot of other bumper plates out
there so it's kind of crazy to me how
much thinner these Rogue plates are one
thing I really like about both of these
plates though is that the seams on both
of them are almost non-existent so a lot
of bumper plates mainly those of lesser
quality you're going to find you know a
really hardcore seam that either sticks
out on either side right here or right
down the middle and since neither one of
these really have that
I think they're going to last you longer
than a lot of those other bumper plates
will and it's really just going to
extend the lifespan they should last
around 10 years or so
all right so which bumper plates should
you buy well honestly guys you can't go
wrong with either one of these plates
they're both a really good option
they're both going to get the job done
for a really long time there's just a
few things you might want to factor in
as you go to make that decision so let's
talk about money it's probably going to
be you know the main deciding factor for
a lot of people and if that's the case
you're probably going to want to go with
rep because you don't have to pay for
shipping on their individual payers and
the full sets are also a little bit
cheaper than the ones that Rogue has to
offer plus you know rep has more full
sets for you to buy as well as a heavier
set so the 370 pound set it's going to
be cheaper than if you were to go for
the 260 pound set from Rogue and then
you know adding on individual pairs to
reach 370 pounds but for somebody who's
wanting to load on a bunch of plates for
a super heavy lift probably going to
want to go with Rogue because their
plates are significantly thinner all the
way across the board at the end of the
day though I mean nobody can make this
decision except for you I would just
suggest keeping those things in mind as
you're doing that all right well that's
a wrap on today's comparison between
these Rogue bumper plates and these rep
Fitness bumper plates honestly you know
once again I don't think you can go
wrong with either one of these bumper
plates it's really just going to boil
down to your budget and how much space
you need on your loading sleeves thanks
for hanging out with me guys I hope this
video was really helpful and I was able
to answer any questions you may have
about either one of these bumper plates
and maybe even make your decision a
little bit easier if you are deciding
between these two right here as always
stay on the lookout for my next video
but for now you should absolutely head
over to barbin.com and you can read more
about this comparison right here just
search bar Bend Rogue bumper plates
first rep bumper plates you'll find
everything that I talked about here
today I'll catch y'all later
[Music]
thank you